A Guide to the Methodist Church Records
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #38-567
Methodist Church Records 1863-1932
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
38-567
ca. 30 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit 1932 Oct 10, 1933 Feb 15
Scope and Content
This collection (1863-1932) contains 28 bound volumes and two folders of records for the Methodist Episcopal Church, South, of Virginia. The Methodist Church Records are on deposit at the University, placed on loan by the Rev. M. F. Draper and the Rev. L. P. Bland on October 10, 1932 and February 15, 1933.
Container List
- Batesville--Bound Volumes
  - Batesville Circuit Church Register containing a pamphlet Fiscal plan of the Virginia Conference ... M. E. Church, South, 1863-1893 (Box Box 1)
  - Batesville Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1889-1893 (Box Box 1)
  - Batesville Membership Records and Batesville Quarterly Conference Records, 1890-1896, 1892-1889, 1904-1907 (Box Box 1)
  - Batesville Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1918-1922 (Box Box 1)
  - Batesville Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1922-1926 (Box Box 1)
  - Batesville Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1926-1930 (Box Box 1)
- North Garden--Folders
  - Abstract to North Garden land deeded to Methodist Episcopal Church South, 4 Nov 1890 (Box Box 1)
  - History of the Methodist organization in North Garden, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Greene County--Bound Volumes
  - Greene Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1879-1883 (Box Box 2)
  - Greene Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1883-1886 (Box Box 2)
  - Greene Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1906-1910 (Box Box 2)
  - Greene Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1910-1914 (Box Box 2)
  - Greene Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1915-1918 (Box Box 2)
  - Greene Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1919-1922 (Box Box 2)
  - Greene Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1922-1926 (Box Box 2)
  - Greene Circuit Quarterly Conference Records, 1926-1932 (Box Box 2)
  - Greene Circuit Church Register, 1873-1888, 1903-1904 (Box Box 3)
- Stanardsville--Bound Volumes
  - Stanardsville Sunday School Records, 1915-1917, 1920, n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - Stanardsville Sunday School Records, 1919-1920 (Box Box 3)
- Culpeper--Bound Volumes
  - Culpeper Church Register, 1890-1898 (Box Box 3)
  - Culpeper Church Register, 1898-1915 (Box Box 3)
  - Culpeper Treasurer's Records, 1919-1920 (Box Box 3)
  - Culpeper Treasurer's Records, 1920-1921 (Box Box 3)
  - Culpeper Quarterly Conference Records, 1890-1894 (Box Box 4)
  - Culpeper Quarterly Conference Records, 1895-1898 (Box Box 4)
  - Culpeper Quarterly Conference Records, 1898-1902 (Box Box 4)
  - Culpeper Quarterly Conference Records, 1902-1906 (Box Box 4)
  - Culpeper Quarterly Conference Records, 1906-1910 (Box Box 4)
  - Culpeper Quarterly Conference Records, 1910-1914 (Box Box 4)
  - Culpeper Quarterly Conference Records, 1914-1918 (Box Box 4)